Hello everyone, welcome back to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
大家好，欢迎回到EnglishPod。我是Marco。
And I'm Erika.
我是Erika。
And today we're bringing you again our romantic, dramatic, suspense series, I'm Sorry I Love
今天我们再次为大家带来我们的浪漫、戏剧、悬疑系列，《对不起，我爱你》
You Part 7.
第七部分。
So we're gonna find out what's happening with Steven and Veronica.
我们来看看Steven和Veronica之间发生了什么。
Right, in the last episode, Veronica was at the doctor's, she was pregnant.
对，上一集里，Veronica在医生那里，她怀孕了。
But then the doctor told her it was a lie and he made it up and she wasn't even pregnant.
但后来医生告诉她那是谎言，是他编造的，她根本没怀孕。
Exactly.
没错。
So now let's see what Veronica and Steven are gonna say to each other.
现在让我们看看Veronica和Steven会对彼此说什么。
Maybe they will break up?
也许他们会分手？
I don't know.
我不知道。
I don't think so.
我不这么认为。
But let's listen.
但让我们听听看。
Thank God you showed up when you did.
谢天谢地你及时出现了。
He's insane.
他疯了。
Do you think we should call the police?
你觉得我们该报警吗？
Don't worry about it.
别担心。
I'll call my friend and have him take care of it.
我会打电话给我朋友，让他处理这件事。
I can't believe he was stalking you all these years.
真不敢相信他这些年一直在跟踪你。
What a nutjob.
真是个疯子。
I know.
我知道。
Well, he said I'm not pregnant.
嗯，他说我没怀孕。
I'm sorry if I got you all worked up over nothing.
对不起，如果我让你白激动了一场。
I want you to know that I didn't do it on purpose.
我想让你知道我不是故意的。
Don't apologize.
别道歉。
From the moment I met you, not a day has gone by when I haven't thought of you.
从我遇见你的那一刻起，没有一天我不在想你。
And now that I'm with you again, I'm just...
现在我又和你在一起了，我只是……
I'm just scared, Veronica.
我只是害怕，Veronica。
The closer I get to you, the worse it gets.
我越靠近你，情况就越糟。
The thought of not being with you, I mean, I just can't handle it.
想到不能和你在一起，我的意思是，我受不了。
We were made for each other, Veronica.
我们是天生一对，Veronica。
You're my everything.
你是我的全部。
My soulmate.
我的灵魂伴侣。
What can I do?
我能做什么？
Just hold me.
只要抱着我。
I'll always be here for you, no matter what.
无论发生什么，我都会永远在你身边。
And together, we can tackle whatever life throws at us.
一起，我们可以应对生活抛给我们的任何挑战。
I believe in us, Steven.
我相信我们，Steven。
I'm so happy to hear that.
听到这个我很高兴。
I know we belong together.
我知道我们属于彼此。
I love you so much.
我太爱你了。
It was such a romantic moment.
那真是个浪漫的时刻。
And now what happened?
然后发生了什么？
Somebody got shot.
有人中枪了。
Oh my God.
哦，我的天。
I don't know.
我不知道。
This is like so big.
这太严重了。
I can't believe this is happening.
真不敢相信会发生这种事。
Well, it's a very intense drama, but we saw some great words and a lot of great phrases
嗯，这是一部非常紧张的戏剧，但我们看到了一些很棒的词语和很多精彩的短语，
in there when Steven was telling her all these beautiful words, right?
当Steven对她说那些美丽的话时，对吧？
That's right.
没错。
So why don't we look at some of these words now in Language Takeaway.
那我们不如在“语言小贴士”环节看看这些词。
Language Takeaway.
语言小贴士。
Veronica was glad or she was very happy that Steven showed up.
Veronica很高兴，或者说她很开心Steven出现了。
That's right.
没错。
Showed up.
出现了。
So, to show up.
所以，“出现”。
Right.
对。
To come to a place.
来到某个地方。
Okay.
好的。
Or to arrive.
或者到达。
That's right.
没错。
So let's listen to some examples of how we can use show up in different contexts.
让我们听一些例子，看看如何在不同的语境中使用“出现”。
Example one.
例子一。
We were waiting for you like an hour and you never showed up.
我们等了你一个小时，你一直没出现。
Example two.
例子二。
I didn't invite him to the party.
我没邀请他参加派对。
He just simply showed up uninvited.
他就不请自来了。
Example three.
例子三。
After months of being lost, my dog finally showed up with a family.
失踪几个月后，我的狗终于和一个家庭一起出现了。
All right.
好的。
So I think it's pretty clear now the verb show up.
所以我想现在动词“出现”已经很清楚了。
And I think this verb is a little bit informal, isn't it?
我觉得这个动词有点非正式，对吧？
Yes.
是的。
You wouldn't really tell your boss, hey, I'm waiting for you to show up.
你不会真的对你的老板说，嘿，我在等你出现。
Yeah.
嗯。
It's a bit too informal.
这有点太非正式了。
As you know, the doctor, he was stalking Veronica.
你知道，那个医生一直在跟踪Veronica。
That's right.
没错。
So that's our next word.
所以那是我们的下一个词。
To stalk.
跟踪。
To stalk somebody.
跟踪某人。
S-T-A-L-K.
S-T-A-L-K。
Okay.
好的。
Stalk.
跟踪。
Now, this isn't a good thing, right?
现在，这不是好事，对吧？
No.
不是。
This is bad.
这是坏事。
So what happens when you stalk someone?
那么当你跟踪某人时会发生什么？
You follow them secretly for a long time.
你秘密地长时间跟着他们。
And then maybe you watch them and...
然后也许你观察他们，然后……
Yeah.
嗯。
Like you're standing outside their window watching them get undressed or something.
就像你站在他们窗外看他们脱衣服之类的。
Okay.
好的。
So many famous people have stalkers, right?
所以很多名人都有跟踪者，对吧？
Yeah.
嗯。
Which is the noun.
那是名词。
The noun form, exactly.
名词形式，没错。
So if I am stalking somebody, I am considered to be a stalker.
所以如果我跟踪某人，我就被认为是跟踪者。
Yes.
是的。
So to stalk.
所以是“跟踪”。
So don't do this.
所以别这么做。
So Stephen described this stalker as a nut job.
所以Steven把这个跟踪者描述为“疯子”。
A nut job.
疯子。
Okay.
好的。
Very, very informal and it doesn't really mean anything literally, but it's crazy.
非常非常非正式，字面上没什么意思，但就是“疯狂”的意思。
Yes.
是的。
It means a crazy person.
意思是疯子。
A crazy person.
疯子。
What a nut job.
真是个疯子。
He's a nut job.
他是个疯子。
Okay.
好的。
So would you really call this to someone, like to their face?
你真的会当面这样叫别人吗？
No.
不会。
Definitely not.
绝对不会。
It's definitely impolite.
这绝对不礼貌。
Right.
对。
You can't say to someone, oh, you're a nut job.
你不能对某人说，哦，你是个疯子。
Yeah.
嗯。
But it's not a swear word.
但这不是脏话。
No, but it's a little bit insulting, right?
不是，但有点侮辱人，对吧？
It's like saying you're crazy, but stronger.
就像说你疯了，但语气更强。
Well, the doctor was a nut job.
嗯，那个医生是个疯子。
He was stalking her and she apologized to Stephen for getting him worked up.
他一直在跟踪她，她为让Steven激动而道歉。
Worked up.
激动。
So work up.
所以是“激动”。
To be worked up.
变得激动。
When you get worked up, what happens?
当你变得激动时，会发生什么？
You get really emotional and usually angry or sad or upset, but a negative emotion.
你会变得非常情绪化，通常生气、难过或沮丧，是一种负面情绪。
Okay.
好的。
So you got worked up.
所以你激动了。
So it's always used with the verb to get.
所以它总是和动词“变得”一起用。
So to get worked up.
所以是“变得激动”。
Okay.
好的。
You get worked up.
你变得激动。
You got worked up.
你激动了。
Okay.
好的。
Very good.
很好。
And well, Stephen got worked up over nothing, but he didn't mind.
嗯，Steven白激动了一场，但他并不介意。
He said she is his love and he called her his soulmate.
他说她是他的爱，他称她为他的灵魂伴侣。
His soulmate.
他的灵魂伴侣。
Soulmate.
灵魂伴侣。
That's right.
没错。
That's a very romantic word, meaning the perfect person for you.
那是一个非常浪漫的词，意思是你的完美伴侣。
Right.
对。
Your other half.
你的另一半。
Yes.
是的。
Okay.
好的。
So your soulmate is that perfect compliment for you.
所以你的灵魂伴侣是你的完美互补。
And it's usually romantic, right?
而且通常是浪漫的，对吧？
Usually romantic, but sometimes you might use it with your very, very, very best friend.
通常是浪漫的，但有时你可能会用它来形容你非常非常非常好的朋友。
Okay.
好的。
Because you understand each other.
因为你们彼此理解。
Yeah.
嗯。
You know what the other one's thinking.
你知道对方在想什么。
You're the perfect fit together.
你们是完美的一对。
Okay.
好的。
Soulmate.
灵魂伴侣。
Very good.
很好。
Well, we've seen some really interesting words.
嗯，我们看到了一些非常有趣的词。
So why don't we listen to our dialogue again, and then we'll come back and look at some
那我们不如再听一遍我们的对话，然后回来看看一些
of the phrases that were used.
用到的短语。
Thank God you showed up when you did.
谢天谢地你及时出现了。
He's insane.
他疯了。
Do you think we should call the police?
你觉得我们该报警吗？
Don't worry about it.
别担心。
I'll call my friend and have him take care of it.
我会打电话给我朋友，让他处理这件事。
I can't believe he was stalking you all these years.
真不敢相信他这些年一直在跟踪你。
What a nut job.
真是个疯子。
I know.
我知道。
Well, he said I'm not pregnant.
嗯，他说我没怀孕。
I'm sorry if I got you all worked up over nothing.
对不起，如果我让你白激动了一场。
I want you to know that I didn't do it on purpose.
我想让你知道我不是故意的。
Don't apologize.
别道歉。
From the moment I met you, not a day has gone by when I haven't thought of you.
从我遇见你的那一刻起，没有一天我不在想你。
And now that I'm with you again, I'm just scared, Veronica.
现在我又和你在一起了，我只是害怕，Veronica。
The closer I get to you, the worse it gets.
我越靠近你，情况就越糟。
The thought of not being with you, I mean, I just can't handle it.
想到不能和你在一起，我的意思是，我受不了。
We were made for each other, Veronica.
我们是天生一对，Veronica。
You're my everything.
你是我的全部。
My soulmate.
我的灵魂伴侣。
What can I do?
我能做什么？
Just hold me.
只要抱着我。
I'll always be here for you, no matter what.
无论发生什么，我都会永远在你身边。
And together, we can tackle whatever life throws at us.
一起，我们可以应对生活抛给我们的任何挑战。
I believe in us, Steven.
我相信我们，Steven。
I'm so happy to hear that.
听到这个我很高兴。
I know we belong together.
我知道我们属于彼此。
I love you so much.
我太爱你了。
That was a little bit more clear this time, but now I want to look at some phrases in
这次清楚多了，但现在我想看看对话中的一些短语，
the dialogue and see how they can be put together.
看看它们是如何组合在一起的。
Putting it together.
组合起来。
So Veronica apologized to Steven for getting him worked up over nothing.
所以Veronica为让Steven白激动了一场而道歉。
Over nothing.
白费。
Now it's the complete sentence.
现在这是完整的句子。
I'm sorry for getting you worked up over nothing.
抱歉让你白激动一场。
So over nothing means for no reason, right?
所以“over nothing”就是“无缘无故”的意思，对吧？
Right, exactly.
对，没错。
So why don't we listen to some other examples of how we can use over nothing.
那我们不如听一些其他例子，看看怎么用“over nothing”。
Example one.
例子一。
You always get angry over nothing.
你总是无缘无故生气。
You have such a bad temper.
你脾气真差。
Example two.
例子二。
I called the police last night over nothing.
我昨晚无缘无故报了警。
I thought I had a thief in my house.
我以为家里进了贼。
Example three.
例子三。
Let's not fight over nothing.
我们别为小事吵架。
Let's just have dinner in peace.
咱们安安静静吃顿饭吧。
Okay so we see you can use many different verbs together with over nothing.
好的，所以我们看到你可以把很多不同的动词和“over nothing”搭配使用。
So get excited over nothing, get angry over nothing, get upset over nothing.
比如无缘无故兴奋、无缘无故生气、无缘无故难过。
Exactly.
没错。
Very good.
很好。
So over nothing.
所以是“over nothing”。
And now for our next phrase.
现在来看下一个短语。
So when Steven was telling Veronica how much he loved her, he told her, not a day has
当史蒂文告诉维罗妮卡他有多爱她时，他说，
gone by when I haven't thought of you.
没有一天我不在想你。
So not a day has gone by.
所以是“not a day has gone by”。
So that part of the sentence, not a day has gone by, what does he mean by that?
那么句子里的这部分，“not a day has gone by”，他是什么意思呢？
He means basically every day I think of you.
他基本上是说每一天我都在想你。
There hasn't been a moment where I haven't thought of you.
没有一刻我不在想你。
Now how can we change it a little bit?
那我们怎么稍微改一下呢？
What can we change within this phrase?
这个短语里我们能改什么？
Well, you can put in different times.
嗯，你可以放不同的时间。
So not a day has gone by, not an hour has gone by, not a moment has gone by.
所以没有一天过去，没有一小时过去，没有一刻过去。
Not a month, not a year.
没有一个月，没有一年。
Exactly.
没错。
So you can use different times in that phrase.
所以你可以在这个短语里用不同的时间。
But an important thing is that the complement is always negative, right?
但重要的一点是，后面的部分总是否定的，对吧？
That's right.
对。
So it's always followed by a negative.
所以它后面总是跟一个否定句。
Not a day has gone by that I haven't wished you were here.
没有一天过去我不希望你在这里。
So it's followed by a negative.
所以后面跟否定句。
That's right.
没错。
Maybe one more.
也许再来一个。
Not a second has gone by that I haven't missed you.
没有一秒钟过去我不在想你。
Very good examples.
非常好的例子。
Very romantic.
非常浪漫。
Oh Marco.
哦，马可。
Yeah.
是的。
All right.
好了。
And now our last phrase.
现在是我们最后一个短语。
He told her I'll always be here for you no matter what.
他告诉她：“无论发生什么，我都会一直在这里陪着你。”
No matter what.
无论发生什么。
What does he mean by that?
他这么说是什么意思？
Well, regardless of or you know, nothing's going to stop me.
嗯，意思是“不管怎样”，或者你知道的，没有什么能阻止我。
Okay.
好的。
So if I want to get that job, I'm going to get it no matter what.
所以如果我想得到那份工作，无论如何我都会得到它。
So nothing's going to stop you.
所以没有什么能阻止你。
Now we can change the WH word, what, at the end, right?
现在我们可以把结尾的疑问词“什么”换成其他词，对吧？
Yeah.
是的。
With other ones.
换成其他的。
Exactly.
没错。
So, no matter where you are, I will find you.
所以，无论你在哪里，我都会找到你。
Yeah.
是的。
No matter when.
无论何时。
No matter when your birthday is, I will be there.
无论你的生日是什么时候，我都会在那里。
That's right.
没错。
You can see how you can use different WH words here.
你可以看到这里如何使用不同的疑问词。
Okay.
好的。
Very good.
非常好。
And it's a very common phrase, right?
这是一个很常见的短语，对吧？
No matter what.
无论发生什么。
No matter where.
无论在哪里。
No matter when.
无论何时。
No matter why.
无论为什么。
No matter how.
无论怎样。
Yeah.
是的。
No matter how.
无论怎样。
Okay.
好的。
So those were some really great phrases and I think you can play with them a little bit,
所以这些是一些非常棒的短语，我觉得你可以稍微玩转一下它们，
change some things and then you can use them in your everyday life.
做一些改动，然后在日常生活中使用。
Right.
对。
But why don't we hear them again one more time in context with the dialogue.
但我们不如再听一遍它们在对话中的上下文吧。
Thank God you showed up when you did.
谢天谢地你及时出现了。
He's insane.
他疯了。
Do you think we should call the police?
你觉得我们该报警吗？
Don't worry about it.
别担心。
I'll call my friend and have him take care of it.
我会给我朋友打电话，让他来处理。
I can't believe he was stalking you all these years.
真不敢相信他这些年一直在跟踪你。
What a nut job.
真是个疯子。
I know.
我知道。
Well, he said I'm not pregnant.
嗯，他说我没怀孕。
I'm sorry if I got you all worked up over nothing.
如果我为这点小事让你紧张了，我很抱歉。
I want you to know that I didn't do it on purpose.
我想让你知道我不是故意的。
Don't apologize.
别道歉。
From the moment I met you, not a day has gone by when I haven't thought of you.
从我遇见你的那一刻起，没有一天我不在想你。
And now that I'm with you again, I'm just scared, Veronica.
现在我又和你在一起了，我只是害怕，维罗妮卡。
The closer I get to you, the worse it gets.
我越靠近你，情况就越糟。
The thought of not being with you, I mean, I just can't handle it.
想到不能和你在一起，我简直受不了。
We were made for each other, Veronica.
我们是天生一对，维罗妮卡。
You're my everything, my soulmate.
你是我的全部，我的灵魂伴侣。
What can I do?
我能做什么？
Just hold me.
只要抱着我就好。
I'll always be here for you, no matter what.
无论发生什么，我都会永远在你身边。
And together, we can tackle whatever life throws at us.
只要我们在一起，就能应对生活抛给我们的任何挑战。
I believe in us, Steven.
我相信我们，史蒂文。
I'm so happy to hear that.
听到这个我很高兴。
I know we belong together.
我知道我们注定在一起。
I love you so much.
我非常爱你。
Okay Erika, so who do you think got shot?
好了，埃里卡，你觉得谁中枪了？
I don't know, but I'm starting to think this story is becoming a soap opera.
我不知道，但我开始觉得这个故事变成肥皂剧了。
Well, it certainly is and well, what do you guys think happened or who do you think got
嗯，确实如此，那么，你们觉得发生了什么，或者谁中枪了？
shot or?
或者？
Who did the shooting?
谁开的枪？
Who shot who?
谁打了谁？
Maybe...
也许……
Was it even a gunshot?
那真的是枪声吗？
Maybe it was just the car.
也许只是车的声音。
The tire could have popped.
轮胎可能爆了。
I don't know.
我不知道。
Exactly.
没错。
So well, come to our website, tell us what you think happens or what you would like to
那么，来我们的网站，告诉我们你认为发生了什么，或者你希望发生什么。
happen because I know many people are expecting a little bit more romance maybe and less drama.
之所以会这样，是因为我知道很多人可能期待多一点浪漫，少一点戏剧性。
But if you have any questions about the language in this lesson, please visit the website at
但如果你对本课的语言有任何疑问，请访问网站
EnglishPod.com.
EnglishPod.com。
Exactly.
没错。
Erika and I are always there to answer your questions and well, anything you guys need.
我和Erika随时都在那里回答你们的问题，嗯，任何你们需要的。
Anything?
任何事？
Anything.
任何事。
Well, thanks for listening to this lesson and until next time, goodbye.
好了，感谢收听本课，下次再见，拜拜。
Bye!
拜拜！